( WIND BLOWS )
( DOG BARKS )
( WOMAN SOBS )
( I PURCELL : Dido 's Lament )
♪ When I am laid
♪ Am laid in earth
♪ May my wrongs create " ;
( MAN MUMBLES )
( MUMBLING CONTINUES )
I don 't believe it !
No pulse .
No pulse , no ...
( HE WHIMPERS )
( MUMBLING INCOHERENTLY )
( DRAMATIC MUSIC )
A little after midnight ,
the old caretaker was awakened by a terrible sound .
Whimpering pitifully .
The sound came again ,
faintly ,
only this time he was sure it was human .
The graveyard was silent , except for the steady padding of his feet
as he went around the tombstones .
" Hello ! Is someone there ? Someone ? "
There was nothing , no-one .
As he stood there , scratching his head ,
feeling something of a damn fool ,
he happened to look down .
And there at his feet ,
someone had been buried that very afternoon .
The grave had been disturbed ,
the soil was upset and the cross lay on its side .
" Respect , " he muttered ,
sure now that he was the butt of a practical joke
so he smoothed out the soil
and set the cross back upright , at the head of the grave .
And then he went back to his bed .
But outside , in the graveyard ,
in the wind
there was still a faint wisp of sound .
Almost like a song .
I 'm alive ,
still alive .
Alive .
God !
Marvellous story . Marvellous .
I think that was the worst shocker we 've had in years .
Damn near scared the pants off me , I tell you .
Yes , well , I don 't know about you , but ...
- ( CLOCK CHIMES ) - ... I could do with another brandy .
- Hear , hear ! - Maybe a big cigar .
I 've got to go to bed .
- So early ? - I haven 't been sleeping well lately .
Besides , it 's late . It 's getting cold .
- And Milly will be waiting up to ... - Pour some hot chocolate down me .
Well , I 'll drive you home , Doc .
You know , mark my words , ten years from now ,
80 % of the young men of this country will be wearing ties only to weddings .
And to funerals too , perhaps .
I 'd feel is if I was naked .
Well , it 's time we all went home . Come on , Doc .
You look terrible . Are you sleeping all right ?
- Dammit to hell ! - Well , are you ?
Gentlemen , before you go ...
I would like to propose a toast .
To us ! Chowder Society !
- The Chowder Society . - The Chowder Society .
- The Chowder Society . - ALL : The Chowder Society .
( EERIE MUSIC )
( SPLASHING )
- Who are you ? - Sleeping .
- Who are you ? - Woke me .
Tell me .
David .
Who are you ?
You know .
I know ?
I am you .
No .
Cold .
What are you ?
( SCREAMS )
( PHONE RINGS )
Donny ?
Come home , Donny .
There 's been a terrible accident in New York .
Your brother is dead , son .
Come home right away .
Now arriving at Gate Three from New York , Hartford and Springfield .
Now arriving at Gate Three from New York ...
Be careful now .
... and Springfield .
Hello , Dad .
Is this all you have ?
I 'm fine .
- Passengers holding tickets ... - Look at you .
I 'm OK , Dad .
TANNOY : Your gate is Four .
RADIO : Break out the snowmobiles , boys and girls .
Two inches of that lovely white stuff already on the ground
and a massive cold from ' heading our way .
Talking about it might help .
Right .
How 's the writing coming ?
I 've had other things on my mind .
And the teaching ?
I didn 't finish out the term .
Oh , Don .
So what do you think happened to him , Dad ?
It was an accident .
Is that what you told everybody ?
What ? That he fell ?
That 's what they said .
I don 't give a damn what anybody said .
I know something happened to him in New York .
You 're shouting .
Jesus Christ , Dad ! I 'm telling you something happened .
- I think he may have been murdered ! - Stop it !
( CLOCK CHIMES )
I knew the girl he was going to marry .
I slept with her , Dad .
Do you hear me ?
I slept with her .
You come here looking like God knows what ,
your brother not even in his grave yet ...
Dad ...
And you start carrying on about having sex with his fiancée .
Dad !
Isn 't it about time you straightened out ?
Somehow .
Dad
shadow of death , I will fear no evil ,
for thou art with me ,
thy rod and thy staff , they comfort me ...
- Thou preparest a table ... - David !
Surely goodness and mercy shall follow me all the days of my life ...
( MUMBLING )
David .
( CRIES OUT )
It 's Don .
Oh .
I didn 't know where I was for a moment .
You were having a bad dream .
Oh , was I ever .
I think I 'll turn in .
You know , I ... I ...
You 're all I have left now , you know .
Maybe ...
Maybe if the weather lets up , you and I can go fishing one day .
I 'd like that .
Me too .
Stay around a few days and help your old man outwith a few things .
Whatever you say . Sure .
Don 't forget to lock up , will you , girl ?
( SOBBING )
- ( HE CRIES ) - Wake up !
- Wake up ! - ( shouts ) No ;
Ricky , for God 's sake !
Stella .
Thank God .
Here .
You poor darling .
Better ?
Do you want to tell me about it ?
No , no , no .
Oh .
Those gruesome stories you tell each other ,
it 's a wonder you can sleep at all .
What are you old fools up to ?
Black magic .
Oh , that .
( MUMBLING )
( INDISTINCT CRY )
( CLANGING )
( LOUD ORGAN BLAST )
Dad ?
( SOBBING )
Dad ? Dad , you OK ?
Fine , fine .
You sure ?
It was just ... Just a dream .
( SOBBING )
( DOOR CREAKS )
Morning , Mr Mayor .
Everything OK ?
Wife and I were sorry about your loss .
Terrible thing .
David !
( WIND HOWLS )
What the hell is he ... ?
WOMAN : Ned ?
Ned !
( SCREAMS )
Holy shit !
( WOMAN GIGGLES )
( GIGGLING GETS LOUDER )
( PHONE RINGS )
Thank God you 're back .
Everyone 's been calling about poor Mayor Wanderley .
He 's a ninny ! So are the two of you if you keep believing such twaddle .
He saw him .
Edward was doing something on that bfldge .
I can 't imagine what , but something .
I have another idea ...
We 've got to help the boy .
You talk as if he was 12 years old .
I 'm sure Edward left him well provided for .
Why don 't you tell him how grateful he should be ?
Take it easy now .
To know a man over 50 years ,
you 'd think you knew what he was capable of .
You 're not doing your blood pressure any good .
My blood ?
Mr James , it 's Joel Brenner over at the Urbanite .
Wants to know if you 'll write something about the Mayor for the paper .
Ricky , you take care of it .
What shall I say ?
My God ! He went off the bridge .
Say whatever you damn please .
I can 't believe it .
- Come on , you 'd better ... - I can 't believe it !
Come on . You 'd better go home now .
- You ... You ... - I 'll call you later .
You knew him as well as I did , Ricky .
He couldn 't . I don 't believe it .
Not now , Ricky .
Yes , now .
My God , Sears .
Something 's happening . I can tell .
Something terrible .
You can be very persistent .
Persistent without being a bully .
That 's a very nice quality , Ricky .
Don 't try to bamboozle me .
It 's a few bad dreams .
And the monthly spook story .
- Now , come on , let 's get to work . - You 're dissembling .
It 's beneath you .
All right . What would you advise ?
I don 't know .
We 've got to do something .
( FAINT LAUGHTER )
( LAUGHTER )
Hello .
What are you doing here ?
Answer me . I won 't hurt you .
Answer the man , Penny .
Hello , Mr Hawthorne .
What are you doing here ? What do you want ?
We want to play .
Isn 't that so , little brother ?
You can 't stay here . You 're breaking the law .
Is that so ?
You 're trespassing here , illegally .
No .
No , we 're not .
We know the owner .
- There is no owner . - Sure , there is .
We 've spoken to her .
Who ?
Our friend .
Our new friend .
- No-one lives here . - Someone lived here .
Someone fantastic .
Huh ?
You 've lived in this town all your life , and you don 't know ?
What ?
He knows , doesn 't he , Fenny ?
- No ! - Maybe he 'd like to play , Fenny .
Maybe it 's time he joined our little game .
You 're going to be seeing some unusual and interesting things
before we 're through , Ricky .
You might say you 're going to be having the time of your life .
You know , Ricky , you 're not going to know if you 're reaping or sowing .
You won 't know up from down , and Ricky ...
We 're going to tear the soul of this pathetic town
and crush its bare bones between our teeth .
Fenny did good , didn 't he , lady ?
Excellent .
You liked that , didn 't you ?
I loved it . Now , I 'll tell you what we 're going to do next .
That 's him .
Gregory Bate .
Are you sure , Mr Hawthorne ?
Positive .
( CHURCH BELL RINGS )
The evidence , taken as a whole , leads me to only one possible conclusion .
That Edward Charles Wanderley , his mind in a state of confusion ,
took his own life .
Get them out of that house today . Do you hear me ?
I 'm sure everybody has by now .
Don 't smart-ass me .
Just get them out of there .
Sears James , I don 't suppose there 's any man alive
who ever got in the last word with you .
I should hope to hell not .
Mr Hawthorne ...
Meet me at the Village Pump in half an hour .
It 's just like Mr Hawthorne said , Walt . Bate is crazy .
" Extremely unstable , " it says here .
He and the boy escaped from a state mental hospital about a month ago .
And Walt ...
He was a member of some kind of occult order back in California .
Geez ! What a pair .
Mm ... Walt .
What about this occult business ? Do you think there 's anything to it ?
I ain 't no Freud .
Damn funny world ! Getting to be a damn funny world .
The strangest things pop into my head .
I was just thinking that sidewalks have changed the world .
- One of my earliest recollections is ... - Mr Hawthorne ...
Call me Ricky . Everybody does .
Getting back to sidewalks .
- Your father and I used to ... - Mr Hawthorne ...
You didn 't ask me here to talk about sidewalks , did you ?
No .
Sears would brain me for saying this .
But I think we 're in danger - all of us .
Milburn , the Chowder Society .
Especially the Chowder Society .
Who is this ?
Never gonna find nothing .
Only a pair of loonies .
Cockamamie !
Someone 's idea of a joke .
Agh !
( BIRD SQUAWKS )
( WHIRRING )
The Lord is my shepherd .
I shall not want .
He maketh me to lie down in green pastures .
- He restoreth my s ... - How did you get in here ?
Such a tragedy .
I 'm so very sorry .
What kind of welcome is that , Don ?
Someone 's died here .
What do you want ?
How do you know my name ?
To look ...
- To touch . - ( PLAYS ORGAN NOTE )
Who are you ?
My name is Gregory Bate .
Although I 've been known by other names , in other places .
Get out !
Are you afraid , Don ?
Will you be afraid when you walk
through the valley of the shadow of death ?
You 're crazy .
Great treats are in store for you and your old friends .
Imagine .
- Just imagine . - Get the hell out !
We 're full of surprises , aren 't we , Fenny ?
- Egh ! - Good boy .
We do have something special for Don , don 't we ?
It 's a little present from our benefactor .
Where did you get that ?
SEARS : Every winter , ice on the power lines ...
You should see yourselves .
You look like three owls .
Leave the candles , Milly .
You 're giving each other the willies with these meetings .
- He 's found a picture of her . - Who ?
- Don . - That 's not possible .
- I thought we ... - I 'm afraid Edward kept one .
What have you told him ?
Nothing .
I wanted to . I like the boy .
The circle has held this long .
Maybe he can help us .
Change is change for the worse .
Spoken like a true lawyer .
We can feel things watching us and following us
and we dismiss them as fantasies .
We have nightmares and try to forget them .
Now that Edward 's gone , I fear ...
I very much fear that more of us are going to die .
I think he 's right .
I told him you weren 't to be disturbed .
That 'll be all , Milly .
Milly ...
Well , then , I 'll just leave you gentlemen to your private business .
Well , young man
do you have something to say to us ?
I want to buy my way into the Chowder Society .
Buy ? What did you say ?
With a story . Isn 't that the price of admission ?
- I 'm sorry , Mr Hawthorne . - Ricky .
But it 's worse than you know . At least two people have already died .
My brother was the first .
I think this is a ghost story .
I had landed a
a year 's teaching job
at a small liberal arts college just north of Orlando , Florida .
Pretty unromantic stuff , really .
Just a couple of sections of an undergraduate course
in American Literature .
I was seeing ...
I was sort of seeing this other instructor called Helen Kayon .
Mr Wanderley .
Who 's that ?
The dean 's new secretary , just started today .
How did she know who I was ?
Must be those blue eyes of yours .
Right !
- Call me tonight . - All right .
" And the first thing she does is seduce him .
" The first thing he does is to be seduced .
" And the second thing they do is hug their sin in secret
" and gloat over it .
" And try to understand it . "
( BELL RINGS )
" Which is the myth of New England . "
Between now and the next time we meet ,
I 'd like you to think about what D H Lawrence meant when he wrote that .
You have a question , Mr Solt ?
Yeah , the part about seduction .
Yes ?
Could you be a little more specific ?
( THEY LAUGH )
Next time .
( TYPEWRITER CLICKS )
So you 're working late , eh ?
Mr Wanderley .
Now , that 's not really fair , is it ?
You know my name and I don 't know yours .
Alma .
Alma Mobley .
- Shall I tell the dean ... ? - Oh , no , not right away .
He 's ...
I really stopped by to see you .
I wondered , if you 're not busy tonight ,
if you 're not doing anything special , maybe you 'd like to join me for dinner .
I mean ...
Oh , Wanderley , you must have been reading my mind .
You 've been doing exemplary work , Donald .
Thank you .
I don 't know what your plans are ,
but I was thinking maybe we should extend your stay here another year .
Close your eyes .
Make a wish .
Whoo !
( THUNDER ROLLS )
If you want to make love to me , you 'd better hurry .
( MUSIC PLAYS )
Do you like it ?
It 's beautiful .
( THUNDER BOOMS )
I 'm frightened of thunder .
I guess I 'd better stay here tonight .
Yes .
ALMA : Ah ! I want you !
I want another kiss .
We 're going to be late .
I don 't know anything about you , you know .
There 's nothing much to know . I 'm just an old-fashioned girl .
I 'll say .
Come on , tell me .
Not now .
Well , where are you from ?
You 're English , right ? So how 'd you wind up down here ?
None of that matters .
I want to know about you .
Tell me where you live .
Ah ... It 's just a couple of rooms .
No , no . Where you grew up .
Milburn ?
Well , it 's just a grave of a town in New England .
Nothing 's changed there in about 200 years .
It sounds lovely .
It 's not .
It 's boring .
Will you take me there sometime ?
- Yeah . - Promise ?
Yeah , I promise .
( TWO SOPRANOS SINGING )
ALMA : Now ...
I want you , now .
Here ?
Here .
Or never again .
( SINGING CONTINUES )
( RATTLES DOOR )
This door is not to be locked at any time .
( WHISPERS ) It 's Miss Meredith .
( KNOCKING )
Open this door this instant .
Do you hear me ?
( SHE GIGGLES )
Don 't stop .
Don 't stop , don 't stop .
( SHE MOANS )
( MUSIC PLAYS )
You 're not wearing any ...
Um ... Which is illegal .
Did you leave ... ?
( CLEARS THROAT )
Would you both like to order now ?
Come on , tell me . I 've told you everything about me .
No secrets .
All right . No .
There 's no-one else in your life ?
Just you .
Well ! But there was someone ?
A long time ago .
You were in love with him ?
It wasn 't anything like you 're thinking .
Just ... Just tell me then .
Tell me that it doesn 't ...
Have anything to do with you ?
It wasn 't a great love .
No .
Good .
Because I 'm going to be , and I don 't want there to be anyone else .
Just me .
Now , let me tell you where I 'm going to take you next weekend .
You haven 't done any work in weeks .
I don 't care .
I 'm a bad influence .
Yes , you are bad .
You 're terrible .
( SHE SCREAMS )
What is it , Alma ?
Water .
Let 's
elope .
We could ... go to the Greek Islands .
Crete .
Don , I 'd love that .
- But ... - But what ?
I 'd rather go to Milburn .
No , not Milburn .
You 're kidding , right ?
Don 't you want to show me off to your home town ?
I want to meet your family .
Well , my mother died a long time ago .
But your father - he 's still alive .
My father and I don 't get along all that well .
Surely this is different .
This is our wedding .
What 's your brother like ?
He 's more like my father , I guess .
Successful , ambitious .
More of a hunter .
You don 't really want to get married in Milburn , do you ?
I want to get married in the town where you grew up .
The same church .
I want to walk down the aisle in my white dress and veil ,
and I want everyone to be there .
Your father ,
his friends ,
the whole town .
All of Milburn .
I will take you places where you have never been .
I will show you things that you 've never seen .
Alma ?
And I will see the life run out of you .
Are you all right ?
Alma ?
( SHE LAUGHS )
( THUNDER ROLLS )
Do you remember ?
The first night you were here ?
It was raining then .
What is it ?
Let 's talk tomorrow .
Now .
I don 't want to get married for a while .
When ?
I don 't know .
Maybe not at all .
You have to .
I 'm sorry .
You don 't know anything !
No .
( MUSIC PLAYS )
( THUNDER BOOMS )
( MUMBLES ) Alma !
( EERIE WHISTLING )
( CRIES OUT )
Alma , listen ...
Can I help you , Mr Wanderley ?
Where is she ?
Miss Mobley did not turn up for work this morning .
Nor did she phone to say that she would be absent .
The dean is most upset .
You 're lax , you 're lazy ,
you 're slipshod .
You disappear for days on end without saying a word to anyone .
Disappointed .
I thought you made a good start .
Alma ?
That 's it there ?
- Who is it ? - Your brother on 3-2 .
OK .
Hi , Donny .
Hi , David .
I 've been thinking about you . I 'm glad you called .
Dave , I gotta talk to you .
Yeah , I gotta talk to you . I got some amazing news .
What ? Robert Redford bought your life story ?
No , I 'm serious .
Um ... I just don 't know how to tell you .
All right , well , why don 't you try starting at the top ?
OK .
About a month ago , I was up on Columbus Avenue on business
and somebody called out your name .
Uh-huh .
I turned around and there 's this great looking girl .
And she thinks I 'm you , right ?
Well , I hope you got around to telling her .
Yes , I got around to telling her .
What 's her name , Dave ?
Donny ...
She is not the person you think she is .
Shit !
She 's worried you have the wrong idea about her .
Everything about her is wrong .
Get away from her , Dave .
She 's dangerous .
I can understand you being upset .
If Alma had walked out on me to marry you , I 'd sure as hell resent you .
I don 't resent anything .
Oh , come off it ! If you can 't admit you resent me ...
Shut the hell up and listen to me , Dave .
Look at her .
All right ?
She is not real .
And you know ? You know like when you touch her ?
She 's cold .
I don 't think we 're talking about the same woman .
( PHONE GOES DEAD )
When they broke down the door to David 's apartment , no-one was there .
She 'd simply vanished .
There had never been an Alma Mobley .
I can vouch for their merit . Havana ?
What about my story ?
Well , it was quite a tale , young man .
It happened .
Just the way I told you .
Why is she here ?
She must have heard you .
I know you 're scared .
I 'm scared too .
I 'm lucky to have escaped whatever sent David out that window .
But I think ...
If we help each other ...
Sounds like Knute Rockne before a big game .
Doesn 't he , Ricky ?
That 's Alma Mobley .
( CLOCK CHIMES )
I don 't believe you .
JOHN : I knew this was going to happen .
Coincidence .
I don 't think so .
Neither do I.
( COUGHING )
No .
I 'm an old man , and often I 'm rude .
We 'll all be very grateful for any help you can give us .
I knew it ! I just knew it !
Last time I saw Alma ...
she was wearing this .
Where d 'you get it ?
Little present from Gregory Bate .
This had to happen .
- It just had to . - That 's enough !
Oh , no ! No ! We must talk about it .
Please , let me tell you about my nightmares .
" No ! ' Milly !
Please , let 's not stop .
Oh , my friends , my dear , dear friends .
- Easy , John . - No , please .
Please , let me talk about it .
Get out ! All of you .
All this talk of graves and ghouls .
- Please , listen to me . - Out !
No ! Listen to me , please ! Please !
Listen !
( HE SOBS )
( I PURCELL : Dido 's Lament )
♪ Remember me
♪ But , ah !
♪ Forget my fate. a
I 'm not going in there ! No , I 'm not ! Not going in there !
No ! Yeah , maybe .
No , I 'm not going in . No ! No !
It 's just as I told you .
No pulse at all .
She 's dead .
Like I said .
( WOMAN SCREAMING )
No !
John !
Can 't move .
You 're dead .
John , it 's me ...
No pulse .
Milly .
No .
No ! No !
( DOG BARKING )
I 'll be down in just a minute , miss .
Milly ?
Rise and shine , now .
Ah !
Is it late ?
11.30 .
- Oh . - You needed the rest .
Come on , now .
Got you a nice cup of tea .
Though you hardly deserve it after last night .
What do you mean ?
You know very well .
You attacked me .
I what ?
You stared at me as if you 'd never seen me before .
On , Milly .
Forgive me .
Too many of those darn stories .
Too much of that high and mighty Mr Sears James .
Oh , dear God , I 'm tired .
Tell me .
You can trust me .
- Bad dreams again . - Yes , it 's all over .
Daylight now .
John ?
I can 't remember .
She moved .
- Yes , she moved . - Who moved ?
She couldn 't .
Couldn 't have . She ...
There 's no pulse .
She 's dead .
For God 's sake , John . Who ?
She was ...
- No , it 's just the jim-jams . - No !
Tell me .
No , go on , stop fussing .
You 're a stubborn old mule , John Jaffrey .
But I love you .
Drink your tea .
Bossy !
Oh , I almost forgot .
There 's a patient in the waiting room .
- I don 't see patients . - That 's what I told her .
Now , don 't worry about a blessed thing .
I 'm sorry , but the doctor isn 't seeing ...
Milly !
( KETTLE WHISTLES )
( DRAMATIC MUSIC )
John ?
Where is it ?
Here , sit down .
What 've you done with it ?
Let me look .
I was in here before and ...
That woman .
It must have been ...
Galli .
She said her name was something Galli .
Odd sort of clothes .
( WHIMPERS )
Am ... Ambulance .
Get an ambulance .
- Mi / burn County . - Emergency .
Why can 't they hurry ?
Think I 'll take a bite out of you .
Eva !
( WOMAN SCREAMING )
( PHONE RINGING )
Hello ?
Milly ? This is Ricky .
( CHURCH BELL RINGS )
This is the worst story we know .
The worst thing that ever happened to us .
The most dreadful thing .
We thought we could keep it a secret .
Should have known better .
Guilt .
After all this time .
We thought it had nothing to do with any of our problems .
And now John 's dead too .
- If I had ... - Ah , don 't blame yourself .
I used to malign him terribly , but ...
( HE SIGHS )
Eva Galli .
There , I 've said it .
Yeah .
Well , what happened to her ?
That 's obvious , isn 't it ?
We killed her .
The two of you ?
All of us .
The Chowder Society .
In the spring of 50 years ago .
SEARS : It was the start of it all .
The beginning .
( APPLAUSE )
Must have money .
She 's rich .
- Where is she from ? - Europe , I gather .
Eva Galli .
( MUSIC STARTS AGAIN )
She 's ... an angel .
Eva .
Make way .
Good afternoon , Miss Galli . Ed Wanderley . How do you do ?
- Miss Galli . - May I help you , Miss Galli ?
I 'm Sears James . Hello .
( CHATTER CONTINUES )
- We were just on our way ... - Miss Galli ...
Miss Galli , take my arm .
One more year of med school and I 'll come back home .
Milburn needs another good GP .
Bravo !
What about you , Ricky ?
Oh , gosh , Miss Galli , I ...
IIII
Ricky , is Miss Galli the best you can do ?
Oh ...
Eva .
What was the question ?
Your plans after graduation .
Oh , Well ...
My father 's got his heart set on taking me into the firm .
- So ... - Hawthorne and Hawthorne for ever .
And why not ? What 's wrong with that ?
Don 't take any guff from him , Ricky .
Old pencil stubs , out-of-date law books .
And you , Edward ?
Hm ?
Are you going to stay here too ?
What ? In this town ? Not on your life .
Ned 's going to be a famous politician . State Senator , maybe .
Then I 'd like to be President .
( 19303 DANCE MUSIC )
Ah ! The Chowder Society .
Look at you standing here .
This is a dance .
Edward ?
Don 't worry , I won 't eat you .
Thinks she 's too good for us .
I don 't think she 's so ... so much .
Shut up , Nettie .
Ricky , move around to the other side .
In front of Sears .
D W Griffith .
John , take a step to your right .
Stop ! Stay there .
Don 't move , anybody .
John !
Eva , say you 'll stay with us for ever .
I 've only rented the house for the summer .
Why don 't you buy it ? You have lots of money .
Good , good . Keep still , everybody .
Ooh !
Come on !
Six , seven ...
She has to stay , doesn 't she , Ned ?
And ...
Ned ! Ned !
( LAUGHING )
Here we go .
Where are you going ?
For a walk .
I 'll come too .
" All day till evening I watched the rain
" Beat wearily upon the window pane
" I was not sorrowful , but only tired
" Of everything that I ever desired
" Her lips , her eyes , all day became to me ... "
You 're being very bad .
I want you .
Hey.Ned !
- Watch that oar , will you ? - Watch where you 're going .
You don 't mind , do you , fellas ?
( CRICKETS CHIRPING )
Ned ?
Do you want to try again ?
- Ned . - What ?
It 's not the end of the world .
( THEY HUM A NOTE )
♪ The blue of her eyes
♪ And the gold of her hair
♪ Are a blend of the western sky
♪ And the moonlight beams
♪ On the girl of my dreams
♪ She 's the sweetheart
♪ Of Sigma Chi . ♪
Well !
About time !
Ricky ?
Would you drive me home , please ?
Yes , ma 'am .
( LAUGHTER )
You 're drunk .
Goddamn right , I 'm drunk .
So are you .
A toast .
Oh !
Stand up !
( emaeuwe )
Stand up .
Ricky , come on .
To the mysteries of women .
- To women . - ALL : To women !
( emaeuwe )
All women are mysteries to me .
So tell us , Ned ...
Yes ! Come on !
- What ? - Please !
My dear friends .
Don 't hold out . No secrets , remember ?
What was it like ?
It was
awesome !
- Oh ! " Really ?
You have no idea .
She 's a goddess .
- A goddamn goddess . - I knew it !
I knew it .
♪ ... on the girl of my dreams
♪ She 's the sweetheart
♪ Of Sigma Chi . ♪
( DRUNKEN SINGING CONTINUES )
Shhhh !
- ( HOOTS ) - Shhh !
Sh ! Sh !
( emaeuwe )
Sh !
May ... Maybe nobody 's home .
Course she 's home . Her lights are on .
You 're such a little old man .
Ring the bell , Ned .
No , no , wait .
- Shut up . - It 's too late .
Too late ? For what ?
Hello , Ned .
Eva .
You 've brought everyone , I see .
Hi , Eva .
- Eva . - Eva .
Well , are you just going to stand here ?
Or are you all coming inside ?
( emaeuwe )
( MUSIC PLAYS )
All right , John .
Let somebody else have a chance .
John .
I 'm dancing with the goddess .
I think it 's time this Romeo was in bed .
Oh , no , no . Come on , it 's early .
What about my dance ?
You heard the lady .
Let 's go .
You just want her all to yourself , don 't you , Ned ?
I suppose you 're going to spend the night .
Don 't think so .
( CLEARS THROAT )
No .
No ? Why not ?
Sears ... please .
No . I want my dance .
Get your things .
( OTHERS ( assume )
- Let 's go . - Where are we going ?
Come on , we gotta go .
Come on !
Wait !
You 'll get your dance .
( MUSIC STOPS )
You all Will .
Oh , wait , please .
Miss Galli , I can 't dance .
We 're leaving .
Eva .
Aren 't you having fun , Neddy ?
- I 've had enough . - I haven 't .
I think I 'll take a bite out of you .
Who 's next ?
Please .
Eva .
Dance with me , you little toad .
Slut !
Poor Neddy .
Did you tell them all about it ?
Did you ?
If Ifl -
You 're pathetic .
- Shall I tell you the truth of ... ? - No !
Eva ?
Eva , wake up !
Wake up !
Eva !
She 's dead .
She can 't be . Are you sure ?
There 's no pulse .
- I murdered her . - No .
No , it was an accident .
We 'd better call the police .
I 'm going to jail .
Scandal .
I 'm a murderer .
Goddamn murderer .
Look , we 're all in this together .
- Let 's call the police . - No .
- What ? - No .
No , we 've got to hide the body .
Hide it where it will never be found .
Oh , Jesus !
Sears .
Shut up !
Do we really have to do this ?
We have no choice .
- You know what you 're doing , Ned ? - Yes .
( EERIE MUSIC )
Oh , Jesus !
- She moved ! - Oh , my God !
She 's dead . I tell you , she 's dead .
( INAUDIBLE )
No ! No ! Eva !
Eva ! Eva !
Eva ! No !
Eva !
( HE CRIES )
We never talked about it again .
Not even with each other .
Told ourselves it was a trick of the light .
Put it behind us .
Back to work , school .
Got on with the rest of our lives .
Wasn 't she missed ?
The town assumed she 'd got tired of it and moved on .
There was a bit of talk , but it died down .
You could almost feel the sigh of relief that she 'd gone .
You mean nobody ever showed up asking about her ?
It was as if she had never been here .
As if it had never happened .
As if we had dreamed the whole affair .
What about the car ?
Still at the bottom of the Dedham Pond .
And you stayed here ? You never left .
We couldn 't , not for long anyway .
What else could we have done ?
Ruined four more lives ?
We could have gone to the police and taken our chances .
Instead we did this obscene thing .
You think it 's Eva ?
And that somehow or other she 's come back to us , huh ?
Yeah .
So do I.
I think maybe ... in growing old ,
maybe the forces ,
or whatever the hell you want to call them , have increased .
And these stories and these nightmares .
- Maybe the guilt . - Is that what killed Edward ?
And my brother , and Dr Jaffrey .
I think Gregory Bate and the boy ...
are helping her .
I want to go to her house .
I hope you 'll come with me .
I Will .
And where do you think you 're going ?
Out .
You 'll do no such thing .
You 'll march right back upstairs before you catch pneumonia .
But I have to go out .
Where ?
You infuriate me with your secrets .
I 've been married to you for 32 years
and I 'm no closer to you than the day we were married .
I 'll tell you in the spring .
I 'm going to take you to the South of France .
To Antibes , St Tropez , anywhere you want to go .
And I 'm going to tell you the story of my life .
( DOOR CREAKS )
I never thought I 'd set foot in this house again .
If only we 'd been 3O instead of 20 .
What fools we were !
I don 't think anybody 's here .
She 's here .
I 'm sure of it .
You want to try upstairs ?
Nothing will come of this .
You want to stay downstairs , Mr James ?
Not on your life .
It 's hard to believe that all of this was so beautiful then .
The rooms downstairs and her room up here .
Just beautiful .
So was Alma 's .
Agh !
Ow !
( EERIE WHISTLE )
All right , that 's enough .
We 'll all go .
He can 't be moved .
Please , Sears , we 'll stay together .
Ricky , don 't argue with me .
I 'm too old , too tired and too frightened .
Sears !
I 'll be back with help as soon as I can .
I could never make him do anything he didn 't want to do .
You OK ?
Yeah .
All clear so far .
Can you hear me ?
Yeah .
( WOMAN GIGGLING )
Ricky ?
Find anything ?
Just an empty room .
You OK ?
Yeah . I was just thinking ...
What ? About the sidewalks again ?
No , you scamp .
It 's Sears . I 'm worried about him .
A lot of people think I take too much guff from him .
But I don 't mind that .
It 's sort of permanent junior partnership stuff , you know .
What can I do ?
I 've been married to the guy
sure as I 've been married to Stella all these years .
He 'll be OK .
I wonder .
Agh !
( HE MOANS )
EVA : Dance with me , you little toad .
( HE SCREAMS )
( HOOTING )
( WIND WHISTLES )
Maybe he just got stuck in the snow .
He 'd have come back if he was all right .
I don 't like it .
We 'll end it , Ricky .
We 'll lay her to rest .
An old man and a pup , huh ?
We are the Chowder Society now .
( HE GROANS )
Sears was right .
You sound like Knute Rockne .
Have to get you to a doctor .
Be right back .
Thank goodness you came along .
Lucky for both of us , Ricky .
Don 't struggle or I 'll kill you right now , you hear me ?
- You 'll be quiet ? - Yeah .
There 's a good little rabbit .
Why are you doing this ?
Would you like to live for ever , Ricky ?
That 's what she promised us .
Imagine the peace of lying down with your hands across your chest .
You go to hell .
Imagine her waiting for you all these years .
Imagine her sleeping under ice and snow .
Waiting .
The pond .
Would you like to be immortal ?
Even if you must die first ?
Good lord ! She 's in the pond .
Alive .
Still alive .
She tricked you . You won 't live for ever .
- Live longer than you . - Oh , no , you won 't !
( EERIE MUSIC )
( RAT SQUEAKS )
( EVA GIGGLING )
( WIND WHISTLING )
( MOANING ECHOES )
( RUSTLING )
( SIREN WAILS )
You 're out of your skull . You know that , Mr Hawthorne ?
We 've got to hurry .
We 've got to help the boy .
( ICE CRASHES )
Aren 't you even going to say hello ?
Oh , Don , you disappoint me .
I thought you 'd be dying to see me .
( WHISPERS ) Y ... y ... you 're not here .
You 're not here .
Talk sense , Don . You can see me , can 't you ?
You can hear me .
I 'm here .
Get away from me !
Faster .
Poor Don .
Haven 't you been longing for me ?
Waiting for me .
I 've come for you .
You 're dead .
And you will be too ,
dead and wet and cold .
Don 't you want to make love to me ?
Don 't you want to know what you 've touched ?
( HE SCREAMS )
I will take you places where you 've never been .
I will show you things that you have neverseen .
No !
And I will see the life run out of you .
( SCREAMING )
( CHURCH BELL RINGS )